Guide to the Ray Wu papers, [ca. 1966-2007]
Wu, Ray papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ray Wu papers, [ca. 1966-2007]
21-47-3771
Ray Wu
26 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers journal articles and reprints, manuscript reviews, thesis reviews, course material, photographs and correspondence of Professor Ray Wu..
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Molecular Biology and Genetics. Dr. Wu developed the first method for sequencing DNA and some of the fundamental tools for DNA cloning in 1970. He led research on genetic modification of rice and other crops to increase resistance to pests, drought, heat, salt, and other environmental stresses. Dr. Wu died in Ithaca on February 10, 2008.
Ray Wu was born in Beijing in 1928. He received his undergraduate degree from the University of Alabama and his Ph.D. in biochemistry from the University of Pennsylvania in 1955. From 1955 to 1966, Dr. Wu conducted research at the Public Health Research Institute of the City of New York. He came to Cornell in 1966 as an associate professor of biochemistry and molecular biology, became a professor in 1972, and in 2004 was named the Liberty Hyde Bailey Professor of Molecular Biology and Genetics. He served as department chair in the Section of Biochemistry, Molecular and Cell Biology. He founded the China-United States Biochemistry and Molecular Biology Examination and Application Program, which from 1982 to 1989, brought over 400 of the top Chinese students to the U.S. for graduate training. While on sabbatical leave in 1989, he served as director of the Institute of Molecular Biology of Academia Sinica in Taipei, Taiwan. He also served as an honorary professor at Peking University. He held many advisory roles to the Chinese and Taiwanese governments and as science advisor to the China National Center for Biotechnology Development, and chaired the Scientific Advisory Committee of BioAgricultural Sciences (Taiwan), the Advisory Committee to the Transgenic Plan Program, National Science Council (Taiwan), and the Board of Scientific Advisors of the International Center for Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology. He was elected a fellow of the American Academy for the Advancement of Science in 2003; and elected a fellow in the Chinese Academy of Engineering.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers journal articles and reprints, manuscript reviews, thesis reviews, course material, photographs and correspondence of Professor Ray Wu..
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wu, Ray; Cornell University.Dept. of Molecular Biology and Genetics.; Zhongguo ke xue yuan.
Subjects:
China United States Biochemistry Examination and Application.; Genetic engineering.; Transgenic plants.; Crops--Genetic engineering.; Plant genetic engineering.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Some folders have been removed from this collection because of their content. In most, but not all cases, this is indicated in the guide below.
CONTAINER LIST
- Reprints I: Academic Papers and Publications, Symposium Proceedings, Conference Reports, Newsletters. (Box 1)
  Includes papers on rice genetics, and natural and agricultural biotechnology.
- Reprints II: Academic Papers and Publications, Symposium Proceedings, Conference Reports and Correspondence (Box 2)
  Reprints include papers on rice genetics. Correspondence includes that with Post Doctoral candidates and applicants, and that concerning Academia Sinica, Taipei
- Correspondence (Box 3)
  Includes correspondence with Post Doctoral candidates and applicants, and that concerning Academia Sinica, Taipei
- Budget and Salary Summaries and Reports (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "Leora, Sharon": Finances and Budget Summaries (Box 3, Folder 2)
- "Discretionary - Bach"; Web Financial Reports, 2003, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Glorious Sun Grant; Web Financial Reports, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- "Current Summary"; Web Financial Reports, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- "Older Account Summary"; Web Financial Reports, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "Lab Space; Budget", 2000-2005 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- CRIS; Correspondence on Stress Resistant, Transgenic Rice/Maize, 2003, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- "Effort Report to CALS"; CVs, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Annual Reports to CALS, 2002-2005 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Molecular Biology and Genetics Department Business, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Job Candidates, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Department Business, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Staff Evaluations, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Post Doctoral Jobs; Letters of Recommendation, 1986-1997, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Oligonucleotide facility Orders and Phone Bills, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Summary - Small Grants, 1989-1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Faculty Positions - Recommendation Letters, 1994-2005 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Post Doctoral Positions Open, 1992, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- CALS Faculty Meeting Minutes; Ag, 1997, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Albany Medical Center Prize, 2003, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- CRIS; Hatch Proposals, 1995-1996, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Environmental Health and Safety, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- NAS Members, Vote Proposals, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Chinese Academy of Engineering, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Orientation - First Year Graduate International Students, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Correspondence: Kornberg, Watson, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- CAMBIA Orders and License Agreements, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- CAMBIA, Jefferson, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- RGN Manuscripts for Review, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- RGN Manuscripts Accepted, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Rice Genetics Newsletter, Japan (RGN), 2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- RGN MS Reviewers: Joe Calvo, Ann Mayer, Andre Jagendorf, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Kenneth Post, Greenhouses Quarantined; Correspondence: Andy Leed, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Mud Greenhouse, 2004-2007 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- KPL Greenhouse, Sanya Meeting, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, September 2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Cornell New Life Sciences Initiative and ACCEL, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- PhD Students, November 2007 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Articles, 2005-2007 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: Samuel Sun; July 2002 Talk, 2002, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Science Direct Journal, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Letters to Jerry L. Yang, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Jerry Yang - Grant Proposal, 30 October 2007 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Universities in China - General Information, Student Exchange, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Cornell - Notable Botanists (Box 4, Folder 18)
- South Chine Agricultural University, August 2005 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- MUA, 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Ronnie Coffman - International Professor Appointment; Agriculture for World Development, 2003, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Correspondence: Norman Scott, on Cornell-Shanghai Jiao Tong University Exchange; Chinese 9th Five Year Plan, 2000, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- New Life Sciences Building, 28 February 2007 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- AVIVA Antibody Corp., 2001, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- CAU Talk and SEB Meeting, Barcelona, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Bioway Company, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Cornell/BARD Program; Coffman, 2003, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- International Symposium on Rice Functional Genomics, France, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Meetings, 2006, France and Oxford, September, October 2006 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Gordon Conference, Oxford, September, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- "Useful for Slides", Seminar Material, 2003- (Box 4, Folder 32)
- International Rice Genetics Symposium, Philippines, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- International Symposium on Rice Functional Genomics, Tucson, Arizona, June, November 2004 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Beijing Symposium, October 2004 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Department Seminar, Keystone Meeting, San Diego Meeting, February, March 2004 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Seminars: China, July 2004 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Group Meeting Talk: Plant and Animal Genome IX Conference; Informal Seminar, February 2001, October 2002 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Meetings, Correspondence: Zhao Aimin; Slides(Beijing), 2003 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Seminars, Talks, April - September 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Mudd Hall Greenhouses, 1988-1992, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Seminars, Talks, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Seminars, Talks, Symposiums, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Ac/Ds Manuscript to Genome, National Research Council Press, Canada, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Manuscript to Plant Science, Zhengge Zhu, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Rice related Journals and Articles, 2006, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Manuscript, Zhengge Zhu, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Ac/Ds manuscript to Genomics, November 2006-January 2007 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- "Chromosomal 1" Location of Ds transgenic Lines on the Physical and Genetic Maps, 2 January 2004 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Wheat, Articles, Reprints and Copies (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Wheat (China), Articles, 2003-2006 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Frank Annunzio Award, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- COX, Canada, JXB, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- "Vinod, Manuscript"; Rice Genetics Newsletter, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Gly Manuscript to Rice genetics Newsletter, Meenu et al, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Manuscripts to Plant Molecular Biology and Plant Science, 2003, 2004, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- HVA1 Manuscript, Babu, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Manuscripts on Rice for International Meetings; Correspondence on BRAV Symposium, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- PhyA Gene: Manuscripts and Related Correspondence, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Glyoxylase I: Manuscript and Related Correspondence, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Li PCR Manuscript, March 2003 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Physiology and Biotechnology Integration for plant Breeding, Manuscript, Review and Related Correspondence, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- P5C Synthase Manuscript and Related Correspondence with Jin Su (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Trehalose Manuscript to PNAS, 16 October 2002 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- REMOVED Wu/Liu Award, 2007, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- REMOVED Wu/Liu Award, 2006, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, October 2001 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- IPT Senescence (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Stephen Goff; Syngenta, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- REMOVED Wu Awardees, 2005: Jie Sun and Yuan Jiang, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Correspondence: Mike Tsene, InGene Biotechnology Co., December 2002 - October 2003 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Big Greenhouse Planning, February 1988 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Greenhouses, 1997-2003 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Jeffrey Lehman (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Peking-Yale Joint Center, 2000-2005 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Arabidopsis, Plant Growth Rooms, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 37)
- REMOVED Wu/Liu Award, 2004, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- "Phloem" (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Cold Spring Harbor Lab, Weizmann Institute of Science (Box 6, Folder 2)
- REMOVED Wu/Liu Awards, 2005, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- REMOVED Wu/Liu Awards, 1993-2006 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- B.t. Plasmids, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Long and Inverse PCR (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Chinese Biotechnology Companies, 2004, 2005, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Cornell Plant Environmental Stress and Physiology Program, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- "Translation Invention" (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Useful Transgenic Plants and Biotechnology, Newspaper, Magazine and Journal Articles (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Act1(p) versus ubri(p), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Extra Procedures, 1897-1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Expansion Vectors; Insect Proteases, 1988-1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Susan Henry, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- CUSBEA Program; Da-qing Zhang's Report on CUSBEA, 2001-2007 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Extra Reports of Zhang/Chen, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- English Version of Zhang's CUSBEA Article, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Documents Related to CUSBEA, 1980-1982, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Correspondence and Manuscripts: Sam Sun (PEPC), Mariam Stickeln, 2002, 2003, 2005, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Correspondence: Sam Sun; Manuscripts and Programs for Seminars and Symposiums, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Greenhouses, 2002-2004 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Undergraduate Manual for Lab of Dr. Wu (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Tianjin Academy of Agricultural Sciences, Correspondence and Manuscripts, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Department Meetings; Staff Positions, 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Biochemistry, Molecular and Cell Biology: Building Strength and Focus, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Section Report - 1977, including work on Recombinant DNA, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Annual Disclosure Statements; CV, Professor Ray Wu, 1985-1997, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Graduate Advisees, 1996-1998 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Biotech Lab Space, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Seminar: Nucleotide Sequence Analysis, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Chinese Newspapers, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- RESTRICTED until March 2017 Articles on DNA Sequencing and on Professor Wu, 1998, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- RESTRICTED until March 2017 Interview Transcripts, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Manuscript to ISIS; Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1997,1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- DNA Sequencing by Ray Wu; Papers by Cao Yu, William Provine and Lisa Onaga (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Papers on DNA Sequencing by Ray Wu (Reprints), 1955-1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Papers by Ray Wu (Reprints), 1968-1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Frederick Sanger (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Paper to Bulletin De L'Institut Pasteur, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Papers by Ray Wu; Correspondence: Dr. Yu Cao, 1970, 1971, 1972, 1978, 1994, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Ellson Y. Chen (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- NIH Guidelines for Research, 1989-2002 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- NIH Guideleines for Research; Wu's MUAs, 1994, 1995-1996, 2003-2006 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Laboratory Survey Reports from EHS, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- DNA Sequencing Paper; Miscellaneous Papers, 1957, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Hand-outs, Group Meetings, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Meetings and Travel, 2002-2004, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Meeting (Talks), 2002 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Rice Genome; Nature, 2001, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Monod Conference, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- International Rice Research Institute Symposium, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Group Meeting, 2000-2003 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Society of Chinese Bioscientists in America, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Materials for Slides (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Genomics and Bioinformatics Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Gene Sequences, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Meetings; Abstracts, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Photographs: Garden Conference, 1977-1988 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- DNA Sequence Analysis (Reprints), 1984-1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Student Lab Assistant Positions; Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1986, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- REMOVED Undergraduate Students, August - December 2006 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- REMOVED Summer Students, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- REMOVED Undergraduate Students, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- REMOVED Student and Staff Reviews, 1992-1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- REMOVED Undergraduate Students, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- REMOVED Correspondence and Recommendations: Green Cards, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Joint Proposal, Steven V. Beer, March 2006 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Joint Proposal, Steven V. Beer; Correspondence: Chang Sik, 2005-2006 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Correspondence and Reprints: Tung Tien Sung, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Correspondence and Articles on Wheat, 2003-2007 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, October 2006 - August 2008 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Correspondence and Manuscripts: Jianfu Zhang (CAU), May 2006 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Correspondence: June Kwak; Gates Foundation Grant Manuscripts, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Correspondence: David Ho, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Correspondence: Ming Luo, Guidelines on Academic Fraud, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Jiangtao Yu, Application for Permanent Residency, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- REMOVED Tang Cornell - China Scholars Program, December 2006 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- REMOVED Susheng Gan, 2002, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- REMOVED Post-Doc Applicants, 2006-2007 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Kan Wang M.S Review, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Journal of Experimental Biology, Manuscript Reviews, December 2007 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- ASR1 Manuscript 1 Review, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Dr. Zongxiu Sun's Grant Proposal and Related Data, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Correspondence: Dr. Zongxiu Sun, CRRI, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- REMOVED Ping Wang Committee; Graduate Records, 1996-2000, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- M.O Way (Texas A and M University), 2000, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- COX Related Correspondence, 2001-2004 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Reviews of Research Manuscripts, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Review of Research Manuscript, Ju-Kon Kim, June 2004 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Su May Yu: Presidential Science Award and Relevant Research Papers (Box 9, Folder 2)
- USDA Proposal Review, Salt Tolerance, June 2003 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- REMOVED Post Doctoral Applicants, January-June 2006 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Shi Xianglin, Nutritional Sciences, June 2006 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Rice Genome Group, Taiwan, May 2005 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: Qiang Zhang, June 2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Collaborations: Xia (Wheat), Yue/Li (Grass), 2004 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Transgenic Rice Seeds Sent to Collaborators, July 2001 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: Vicki Schaff, Gu Hongya, Luo Ming, 1999-2003 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: Gu Xiacheng, Luo Ming, 1998-2002 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Correspondence and Manuscripts: Zhu Bao-Cheng, Yunliu Fan, 1991-1998 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Monsanto Annual Report, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- CU Institute for Biotechnology and Life Sciences Technologies Charter; Correspondence: James Zhang, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Seed Transfers and Related Correspondence, 1993-1999 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- REMOVED Manuscripts and CV: Yan Xu, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Biotech Advising Committee, China, 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- China National Center for Biotechnology Development (CNCBD): Meeting Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- CNCBD Advisors, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Sabbatical Leave Preparation, 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Manuscripts: HKUST Grant Proposal, ABA Signalling, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- AOF Proposal, September 2002 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Post Doctoral Appointments and Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, Manuscripts and Appointment Letters: Postdoctoral Candidates and Co-workers, 2000-2006 (Box 9, Folder 24-38)
  Includes (in the following order): He Chung Kun, Zhengge Zhu, Chengkun He, Zhihong Lin, Moul Dey, Jai Singh Rohila, Sneh Pareek, Md. Enamul Hoque, Jun Cao, Liang Chen, Jenny Zhang, P. Jayasankar, REMOVED Joan Lee, REMOVED Dheeraj Verma, Meenu Madan and Silan Dai
- Correspondence, Manuscripts, Appointment Letters: Co-workers and Post Doctoral Candidates, 1996-2006 (Box 10)
  Includes (in the following order) correspondence with Qu Xue Ping, Xian Zhang Wu, Li Fengling, Ju Kon Kim, REMOVED Xiao Hong Sun, Shavindra Bajaj, Hui Jiang, Silan Dai, Jin Su, Madhuri Gandikota, Rajinder Jain, Dai Cheng, Bao Dang Wu, Malabika Roy, Steve Daughettee, Rhong Zhao Fu, Men Chi Chang, Xiangfong Chen, Li Fei Lui, Dan Lui, Alice Li, Kenny Lueng and Albert Chan. Also includes Proposals and correspondence related to the Glorious Sun Group, USDA proposals, NSF proposals, abstracts and manuscripts related to AC/DS plants
- CAP Meeting, December 2003 - January 2004 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- "Old Grant Accounts", 2002 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- USDA and CAP Proposals, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- NSF Grant Proposal, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Drought Statistics; Correspondence: Paul Carey, 1999, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Sample Grant Proposals, 1991-2000 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Correspondence and Manuscripts: Susan McCouch, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- NSF Grant Proposal: Rice Ac/Ds, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- "C.K. Heis Result for Susan", 29 July 2003 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- NSF Grant Proposal with Susan McCouch, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Rice Foundation Grant Proposal, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- USDA Grant Proposal with Susan McCouch, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- New Rice Group Grant Proposal; Correspondence: Shannon Pinson, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Joint Group Proposal to NSF with Henry Nguyen and David Ho, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- USDA Grant Proposal, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Old Grant Budget Summaries, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- NSF Grant Proposals, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- NSF Grant Proposals: Drafts, Notes, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Rice: Gene Data, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- REMOVED Work Study Students, 1985-1998 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Employment Guides, 1985, 1989-1993 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- REMOVED Technician Applicants, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- REMOVED Correspondence and Forms: Jennifer Smith, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Undergraduate Assistants, 1992-1998 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- REMOVED "Technician - Past", 1989-1992 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, April 2004 - September 2004 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, January 2004 - April 2004 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Correspondence: Jason Shih, 1997-2004 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Correspondence and Manuscripts: Guangbin Luo (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, Manuscripts and Photographs: Su May Yu, Tony Huang, Chang Hang Chou, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, December 2003 - March 2004 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, Manuscripts and Course Material, 1988-2006 (Box 12)
  Includes correspondence with students, colleagues, co-workers, scientists, corporations, universities in China, and friends. Also includes drafts of Cornell University addresses and symposiums, NAAS Nomination Papers and course material and lecture-notes for BS/BioMB 132 and BS 730
- Correspondence, Manuscripts and Reports, 1999-2006 (Box 13)
  Includes correspondence with students, colleagues, co-workers, scientists, corporations, universities in China and India, and friends. Also includes Undergraduate Laboratory Manuals.
- Ray Wu Society for Life Sciences, 1997-2003 (Box 14, Folder 1-7)
- Biographies, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and Manuscripts: Cao Yu, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
- Publication and Reprints from Molecular Breeding, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from Molecular Breeding, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from Molecular Breeding, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- "Reprints to Xerox" (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from Frontiers in Biology, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from Plant Physiology, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from Discoveries in Plant Biology, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from Plant Molecular Biology, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from Plant Science and Molecular Breeding, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Manuscript and Review: DNA Sequencing Article, Cao Yu, 1998, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from BioTechniques, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Publication and Reprints from Gene and The Plant Journal, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Wu's Publications and Reprints from Plant Molecular Biology, Molecular and General Genetics, Trends in Biochemical Sciences and Plant Science, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 24)
- Wu's Publications and Reprints from Nature Biotechnology, Plant Molecular Biology, Plant Science, Plant Molecular Biology and Genome, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Reprints: DNA Sequencing (Box 14, Folder 26)
- Wu's Publication and Reprints from Advances in Enzymology, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 27)